NGOZICHUKWUKA IKEABA

Address: 57, Palm Avenue, Mushin, E-mail: kebidegozi@gmail.com

Lagos State. LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ngozi-ikeaba

Github: https://github.com/ngokebi

Portfolio: https://ngokebi.github.io/Ngozi- Port

OBJECTIVE/PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A passionate software developer with over 3 years of experience developing and maintaining software products, building core web applications with core PHP and its Framework (Laravel). He is very flexible with different technologies and methodologies.

EDUCATION

University of Benin, Benin City, Edo, Nigeria

10/2012 - 11/2016

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Phone: +234 (0) 814-113-1223

Royal Kriston College, Lagos, Nigeria

09/2005 - 07/2010

(WASSCE) West African Senior Secondary Certificate Examination

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

PHP Development, Laravel Framework, APACHE, MySQL, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, RESTful API integration, Git Version Control, MVC Architecture, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Custom CMS Development, CRM System Development, Responsive Web Design, Website Optimization, Front-End Collaboration, Third-Party API Integration, Scalability and Performance Optimization, Problem-Solving, Teamwork and Communication

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer

05/2020 - Present

Page Financials, Ikoyi, Lagos State

Worked as part of software development teams in the design, development, and support of both new
and existing software products and systems; reporting status, monitoring issues/problems, and
recommending action plans.

- Develop web applications and content management systems within a lamp environment that includes distributed servers and MySQL databases.
- Responsible for supporting existing applications, developing new features for existing applications, and developing new web-based applications.
- Worked with PHP, MySQL, CSS, JavaScript, and Ajax to build a fully web-compliant networking website.
- Coordinated with and managed third-party vendors for various large-scale projects.
- Used JavaScript/jQuery to make an interactive site. Responsible for handling the backend side of the application to make it high-performance, rich, and user-friendly.
- Implementation of rest API services using MVC frameworks and from scratch.
- Worked with the database schema design and normalization for the database accessed by the procedural PHP pages.
- Used Ajax for every page to dynamically display the data without a page refresh.
- Developed and maintained functions, procedures, triggers, and indexes using MySQL database programming language.

IT Support Officer

07/2019 - 04/2020

Page Financials, Ikoyi, Lagos State

- Provided technical support for hardware software and provided exceptional customer service in response to incoming service requests.
- Troubleshoot problems with PCs, servers, software, and communications devices.
- Troubleshoot PC thin and thick client desktop systems, software, peripherals, briefing display devices, and video teleconference devices.
- Provided end-user desktop and networking support with other technicians via phone, email, or in person.
- Adhered to the established IT policies, procedures, and standards and ensured conformance with information systems goals and procedures.
- Improved the system performance by identifying problems and recommending changes.
- Maximized the use of hardware and software by training users, interpreting instructions, and answering
 questions.
- Fixing computer problems like viruses, trojans, malware, etc. (good with understanding computer hardware/troubleshooting).
- Upgrading and replacing the computer parts like video card, sound card, motherboard, power supply, etc.
- Understanding how to manage a server including creating backups necessary.
- High knowledge of Microsoft programs including Excel, Word, PowerPoint, etc.

Assisting in the areas of site support, and project-specific assignments. Providing training as needed to
end-users.

Laravel Developer (Contract)

06/2022 - 06/2023

Petrong Software Solutions, Lagos, Nigeria

- Worked in a team, involved in developing the UI layout and application development using Laravel for responsive mobile applications for the clients (users).
- Develop, record, and maintain cutting-edge web-based PHP applications.
- Used Wamp (windows, Apache, MySQL, and PHP) for development using Laravel.
- Responsible for the design and development of web pages using HTML, and CSS including Ajax.
- Added functionality as an image carousel, on-site website update and media (images/video) upload using technology HTML, jQuery, JavaScript, CSS, and Laravel.
- Created middleware for user and admin authentication and used blade templating engine for rendering dynamic views.
- Migration and seeding of database schema based on the models for the application.
- Added dynamic User profile on the home page using the model, controller, and view (Laravel).

CERTIFICATIONS

- PHP And MySQL Website/ CMS Certificate Udemy (09/2019)
- Microsoft Active Directory Udemy (03/2020)
- Introduction to Laravel 8.0 Udemy (02/2021)
- MySQL Bootcamp: From Beginners to Expert Udemy (07/2022)

PROJECTS

Appraisal Portal - (Page Financials)

https://online.pagefinancials.com/appraisal/index.php

Responsibilities:

An appraisal portal, with an appraisal level of three, staff, supervisor, and manager. I used PHP as the core language and HTML template for the front end. it contains functions like Excel uploads of KPIs, excel uploads of KPIs scores, supervisor and manager scoring, MySQL triggers and functions to calculate KPIs scores, as well as HR reports and User creations. It's currently being used by the company.

Database: MySQL

Technologies: PHP, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript

Investment Webapp - (Page Financials)

https://pagefinancials.com/invest/

Responsibilities:

A multi- Layered Form Wizard to assist Investors in creating investments for themselves. Also, a back-level function to spool the reports and create the investor's account and investment.

Database: MySQL

Technologies: PHP, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript

Taxaide Loan APIs - (Page Financials/Taxaide)

Responsibilities:

A collaboration with Taxaide, I provided them with APIs that will allow their staff to assess our Loan Facilities, i also integrated the repayment line into our system with the APIs they provided.

Database: MySQL

Technologies: PHP, jQuery

Deftpress - (Petrong Software Solutions)

https://deftpress.petrongsoftware.com

Responsibilities:

As a voluntary Developer for Petrong Software solution, I also worked on a Laravel project, where Users can register and subscript to create a single-page website from a list of templates available, I was tasked to create a system where users can edit the website without an admin portal, that is, on-screen editing for the website's texts, images, and color of the template, also I worked on the image carousel functionality and the subscription integration with flutter wave.

Database: MySQL

Technologies: Laravel, ¡Query, JavaScript